A Guide to the Harry Flood Byrd, Sr. Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series V: Byrd Family and Flood Family
  - B. Richard E. Byrd, 1888-1957
    - Hand written draft of a letter by Harry Flood Byrd to Republican National Committee re: Richard E. Byrd's refusal to be a guest speaker, 1932 (Box Box 425)
    - Correspondence of Harry Flood Byrd, Sr. and Richard E. Byrd, 1933-1940 (Box Box 426)
    - Richard E. Byrd Photos: South Pole Expedition Planes, 1937-1940 (Box Box 426)
    - Correspondence of Harry Flood Byrd, Sr. and Richard E. Byrd, 1941-1957 (Box Box 426)
    - Articles and letters re: Death of Richard E. Byrd, 1957-1962 (Box Box 427)
    - Articles and clippings re: Death of Richard E. Byrd, 1957 (Box Box 427)
    - Articles re: Polar Expeditions, 1957 (Box Box 427)
    - Correspondence of Harry Flood Byrd, Sr. re: Richard E. Byrd, 1961-1965 (Box Box 427)
    - Correspondence of Harry Flood Byrd, Sr., Meluilk Grosvenor et al. re: Memorial for Richard E. Byrd, 1961-1965 (Box Box 427)
    - Commissioning of U. S. S. Richard E. Byrd, 1964 (Box Box 427)
  - C. Harry Flood Byrd, Jr.
    - Correspondence of Harry Flood Byrd, Sr. and Harry Flood Byrd, Jr., 1929-1965; 9 folders (Box Box 428)
    - S. 200, An Act, 1965 (Box Box 429)
    - S. 2914, A Bill, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. 3107, A Bill, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. 3164, A Bill; Amend: 946, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. 3488, A Bill, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. 3514, A Bill, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. 3580, A Bill; S. 3580, An Act, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. Joint Resolution 127, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. Joint Resolution 130, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - S. Joint Resolution 148, 1966 (Box Box 429)
    - Civil Rights Act, speech, statement, and documents, 1966 (Box Box 429)
  - D. Members of the Byrd Family
    - Papers, 1917-1943; 9 folders (Box Box 430)
    - Papers, 1944-1957; 5 folders (Box Box 431)
    - Letters, cards, telegrams to Harry Flood Byrd on death of Mother, 1957; 6 folders (Box Box 432)
    - Papers, 1958-1965; 3 folders (Box Box 433)
    - Get well cards and letters for Mrs. Harry Flood Byrd, 1963 (Box Box 433)
    - Biographical information on William Byrd, III, n.d. (Box Box 433)
    - Bill of Exchange of William Byrd, 1775 Nov 26 (Box Box 433)
    - Byrd Family Photographs, including photo of Harry Flood Byrd & FDR, n.d.; 3 items (Box Box 433)
    - "Rosemont" as first built, n.d. (Box Box 433)
  - E. Flood Family
    - 1. Hal D. Flood
      - Political Papers of Hal D. Flood, 1896-1913 (Box Box 434)
      - Requests for contributions of Hal D. Flood, 1916-1921 (Box Box 434)
      - Letters urging H. D. Flood to run for Senator, 1919-1920 (Box Box 434)
      - Letters urging H. D. Flood to announce his candidacy for Governor, 1920-1921; 2 folders (Box Box 434)
      - Notes, Speeches re: Good Roads Association, etc., 1921 (Box Box 434)
      - Papers re: State Democratic Committee and E. Lee Trinkle's Candidacy for Governor, 1921 (Box Box 434)
      - Clippings re: Henry D. Flood, 1908 (Box Box 435)
      - Tax Receipts and Correspondence re: Taxes, 1908-1923 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Stock Certificates, 1914-1918 (Box Box 435)
      - Correspondence re: Notes and Deeds, 1915-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Deeds, 1917-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Liberty Bonds of H. D. Flood, 1918-1922 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Insurance Policies, 1918-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Liberty Bonds, 1919-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Correspondence of L. D. Arnold, 1919-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Loans by H. D. Flood, 1919-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Loans to H. D. Flood, 1919-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers concerning endorsed notes, 1919-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Receipts, correspondence with the Bank of Appomattox, 1920-1921 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Stock subscriptions, 1920-1922 (Box Box 435)
      - Papers re: Renting of Farms, 1906-1911 (Box Box 436)
      - Miscellaneous Papers re: Farming, 1912-1919 (Box Box 436)
      - Papers re: Registration of Holsteins and Horses, 1913-1920 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with Harry V. Cole re: Sale of Cream, 1914-1915 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence between T. L. Drinkard and H. D. Flood, 1916-1920 (Box Box 436)
      - Papers re: Sale of Filly, 1917-1918 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence between S. C. Drinkard and H. D. Flood, 1917-192 (Box Box 436)
      - Papers re: Sale of Eldon Farm, 1917-1920 (Box Box 436)
      - Miscellaneous Papers re: Farming, 1917-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Papers re: Eldon Farm Dairy, run by Fletcher T. Guill, 1918-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with Andrew, Albert, and Marshall Ferguson re: Farming, 1918-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with W. H. Byrne, County Agent, 1918-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with C. W. and J. M. Doss, 1918-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with Toney and A. T. Ferguson re: Farming Matters, 1918-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with Pete, T. H., and W. H. Stanley re: Farming, 1918-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence between Johnson Russell and H. D. Flood re: Sale of Horses, 1919-1920 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence between W. M. Carter and H. D. Flood, 1919-1920 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with C. S. Carter re: Farming, 1919-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with Holmes E. Smith re: Farming, 1919-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Correspondence with Thomas and Joel Guill, 1919-1921 (Box Box 436)
      - Papers re: Sales, Tobacco, Farm, etc., 1922 (Box Box 436)
      - Miscellaneous Legal Papers, (especially the Shearer case), 1903-1918 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Bailey v. Flood Case, 1904-1919 (Box Box 437)
      - Correspondence re: Robert L. Fitzhugh, B. J. Fitzhugh, and Randolph S. K. Fitzhugh, 1904-1924 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Bailey v. Flood Case, 1904-1920 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: S. E. J. Binford vs. L. H. and L. C. Gillian Case, 1907-1911 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: P. P. Pankey and R. R. Davis vs. the Norfolk & Western Railway Company Case, 1909 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: J. P. L. Fleshman vs. Mary Tanner, 1910-1916 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: W. H. Hyer, Adm'r of Birl C. Wilkes, Dec'd., vs.Nannie M. Wilkes, ex. of S. M. Wilkes, Dec'd., 1910-1918 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Nelson Tindall vs. Va. Safe Deposit and Trust Corporation, 1911 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Bent Creek Bridge (Appomattox Co. vs. C. & O. Railway Co., 1912-1913 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: J. B. Gilliam vs. Thomas S. Bocock's Trustees, 1913 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Anderson vs. Fitzpatrick, 1917 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Injury to Archer Crute, 1917-1919 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Idaho Sugar Case, 1920 (Box Box 437)
      - Miscellaneous, 1920-1921 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: H. D. Flood and M. M. Wyvell vs. H. W. Breckenridge and Jenaette N. Breckenridge Case, 1921 (Box Box 437)
      - Papers re: Settlement of Estate of Mary C. Davis by J. R. Kyle and H. D. Flood, 1902-1915 (Box Box 438)
      - Papers re: Settlement of Estate of Mary C. Davis by J. R. Kyle and H. D. Flood, 1907-1917 (Box Box 438)
      - Clippings re: Senator T. S. Martin, 1919 (Box Box 438)
      - Papers re: Estate of Senator Thomas S. Martin, concerns Peoples National Bank, 1919-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Notes, Receipts re: Estate of Senator Thomas S. Martin, 1919-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Correspondence between H. D. Flood and Thomas S. Martin, Jr., 1919-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Papers re: Estate of Senator Thomas S. Martin, 1919-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Papers re: Estate of Senator Thomas S. Martin, concerning property (Monte Sano), 1920-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Correspondence with Miss Lucy Day Martin (Keats), 1920-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Accounts of the Estate of Senator Thomas S. Martin, 1920-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Correspondence with Continental Trust Company re: Estate of Thomas S. Martin, 1920-1921 (Box Box 438)
      - Correspondence re: Settlement of Martin Estate, 1922 (Box Box 438)
      - Receipts re: Settlement of Martin Estate, 1922-1923 (Box Box 438)
      - Papers re: Estate of Col. R. B. Poore, 1903-1918 (Box Box 439)
      - Papers re: Estate of Col. R. B. Poore, 1906-1923 (Box Box 439)
      - Papers re: Settlement of R. B. Poore Estate, 1914-1923 (Box Box 439)
      - Papers re: Cases concerning the Williamses, 1907-1916 (Box Box 439)
      - Papers re: Williams Estate, Miss Macie Williams, 1911-1913 (Box Box 439)
      - Papers re: Williams Estate, Mrs. E. R. Williams, 1911-1913 (Box Box 439)
      - Papers re: Williams Estate, 1911-1915 (Box Box 439)
      - Papers re: Cases concerning the Williamses, 1911-1916 (Box Box 440)
      - Papers re: Williams Estate, 1911-1918; 4 folders (Box Box 440)
      - Papers re: Williams Estate, Stock and Bond Matter, 1914 (Box Box 440)
      - Papers re: Williams Estate, 1915-1920 (Box Box 440)
      - Papers re: Settlement of the Williams Estate by H. D. Flood and Harry Flood Byrd, 1918-1923 (Box Box 440)
      - Papers re: Settlement of William M. Cabell Estate, 1914-1922 (Box Box 440)
      - Papers re: Settlement of Lightfoot Estate in Lightfoot West suit, 1919 (Box Box 440)
      - Various accounts and notes receivable, 1920-1924 (Box Box 441)
      - Papers re: Automobiles, 1921 (Box Box 441)
      - Correspondence between L. D. Arnold and Harry Flood Byrd, 1921-1922 (Box Box 441)
      - Correspondence with Hon. S. L. Ferguson, Senator from 18th District, Appomattox, Va., 1921-1922 (Box Box 441)
      - Administration Papers of the Estate of H. D. Flood, 1921-1922 (Box Box 441)
      - Miscellaneous, 1921-1922 (Box Box 441)
      - Notes and Correspondence of L. D. Arnold, Secy. to late Hon. H. D. Flood, 1921-1923 (Box Box 441)
      - Assets in settlement of H. D. Flood Estate, 1921-1923 (Box Box 441)
      - Bills, receipts, correspondence, of the estate of H. D. Flood, 1921-1923 (Box Box 441)
      - Papers re: Taxes, 1921-1923 (Box Box 441)
      - Papers re: Stock in Oakcoal Corporation, 1921-1923 (Box Box 441)
      - Estate of H. D. Flood: Insurance policies and payments, 1921-1923 (Box Box 442)
      - Papers showing distribution of H. D. Flood Estate, 1921-1924 (Box Box 442)
      - Papers re: Inheritance Tax on Estate of H. D. Flood, 1921-1926 (Box Box 442)
      - Miscellaneous papers re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1921-1929 (Box Box 442)
      - Receipts, bills re: Bank of Appomattox Account, 1921-1931 (Box Box 442)
      - Completion of mausoleum by Lloyd Brothers, 1922 (Box Box 442)
      - Papers re: Old Dominion Trust Co. and correspondence, 1922 (Box Box 442)
      - Bank accounts of Mrs. H. D. Flood, 1922 (Box Box 442)
      - Papers re: Income Tax due from H. D. Flood, 1922 (Box Box 442)
      - Papers re: Tenants, Rents, Shares, etc., 1922 (Box Box 442)
      - Statements, returns, etc., re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1922-1923 (Box Box 442)
      - Receipts, bills, correspondence re: H. D. Flood Estate, 1922-1923 (Box Box 443)
      - Accounts and Notes payable re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1922-1923 (Box Box 443)
      - Miscellaneous papers re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1922-1923 (Box Box 443)
      - Farm contracts, 1922-1924 (Box Box 443)
      - Papers re: Stock and miscellaneous, 1922-1924 (Box Box 443)
      - Papers re: Sale of Times-Virginian to A. H. Clement and W. M. Wyant, 1922-1924 (Box Box 443)
      - Vouchers of H. F. Byrd re: H. D. Flood Estate, 1922-1930 (Box Box 443)
      - Miscellaneous vouchers re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1923-1933 (Box Box 443)
      - Henry Delaware Flood, Biographical material, 1924 (Box Box 443)
      - Miscellaneious papers re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1924-1928 (Box Box 443)
      - Collections, Disbursements and Land Sales of Estate of H. D. Flood, 1924-1935 (Box Box 443)
      - F. C. Moon Notes, 1925-1926 (Box Box 443)
      - Miscellaneous papers re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1925-1935 (Box Box 444)
      - Miscellaneous papers pending in Estate of H. D. Flood, 1926-1930; 2 folders (Box Box 444)
      - Accounts of Byrd administration of H. D. Flood Estate, 1927-1931 (Box Box 444)
      - Miscellaneous papers re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1928-1931 (Box Box 444)
      - Statements re: Estate of H. D. Flood, 1931 (Box Box 444)
      - Deposits in Account of Harry Flood Byrd, Adm'r., 1931 (Box Box 444)
      - Paid checks of the Flood Estate, 1932 (Box Box 444)
      - Bank books, n.d.; 2 items (Box Box 445)
      - Account books re: Hal D. Flood, n.d.; 2 items (Box Box 445)
    - 2. Members of the Flood Family
      - Papers re: Estate of Joel W. Flood, 1900-1915 (Box Box 446)
      - Papers re: Joel W. Flood vs. Joel W. Flood, Jr., 1905-1907 (Box Box 446)
      - Papers re: Estate of Joel W. Flood, 1914-1920; 3 folders (Box Box 446)
      - Correspondence concerning Joel W. Flood (son) in relation to Estate of Joel W. Flood, 1916-1920 (Box Box 446)
      - Correspondence of Mrs. Joel W. Flood re: Estate of Joel W. Flood, 1916-1921 (Box Box 446)
      - Papers re: Account of Joel W. Flood with The Bank of Appomattox, 1917-1921 (Box Box 446)
      - Papers re: Settlement of Joel Flood Estate, 1918-1920 (Box Box 446)
      - Correspondence re: Estate of Joel W. Flood, 1919-1921 (Box Box 446)
      - Papers re: Settlement of Joel W. Flood Estate by Harry Flood Byrd, 1922 (Box Box 446)
      - Papers of Joel W. Flood, 1922-1925; 2 folders (Box Box 446)
      - Notes endorsed re: Farming Matters, 1925-1931 (Box Box 446)
      - Papers re: Portner Estate, 1914-1921; 4 folders (Box Box 447)
      - Papers of Mrs. Anna Portner Flood, 1922 (Box Box 447)
      - Papers re: Anna Portner Flood Case, 1922-1923 (Box Box 447)
      - Correspondence between Anna Portner Flood and Harry Flood Byrd, 1922 & 1941 (Box Box 447)
      - Vouchers of Mrs. H. D. Flood, 1922-1927 (Box Box 447)
      - Papers of Mrs. Anna Portner Flood, 1923-1924 (Box Box 447)
      - Lists and Accounts of Anna Flood, 1926 (Box Box 447)
      - Papers re: Guardianship of Bolling B. Flood and Elinor F. Flood & Title of Washington lots, 1922-1929; 2 folders (Box Box 448)
      - Returned checks of Harry Flood Byrd, Guardian, 1923-1927 (Box Box 448)
      - Statements of Harry Flood Byrd, Guardian of Bolling B. Flood and Elinor F. Flood, 1926-1931 (Box Box 448)
      - Statements and paid checks of the Guardian Account of Harry Flood Byrd, 1934-1935 (Box Box 448)
      - Discharge of Harry Flood Byrd as Guardian of Eleanor Portner Flood and Bolling Byrd Flood, 1937 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Sale of Washington property, 1910-1920 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Sale of Oakleigh, 1912-1915 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: 613 Lexington Place, N. E., 1913-1921 (Box Box 448)
      - Correspondence re: Mrs. M. B. Anderson, 1916-1918 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Apt. at 2029 Connecticut Avenue, 1917-1920 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: 1258 Columbia Road, N. W., 1917-1920 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Sale of Virginia property, 1917-1921 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Hadleigh Apartment, 1920-1921 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Sale of 1523 New Hampshire Avenue, 1920-1928 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: 1523 New Hampshire Avenue property, 1921-1925 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Sale of Real Estate in Washington, D. C., 1921-1929 (Box Box 448)
      - Notes re: Sale of Real Estate, 1922-1923 (Box Box 448)
      - Papers re: Mr. & Mrs. Ellis in relation to 1523 New Hampshire Avenue, 1927 (Box Box 448)
      - Flood Family, 1941-1965 (Box Box 448)